2005年，科学家在外太空发现
In 2005,  Scientists discovered a distant planet
一颗与地球气候相似的行星
which has a climate almost identical  to that of earth.
2006年，太空总署研发了一个
In 2006, NASA constructed a  transmission device
比以往强大五倍的传输装置
that was many times more powerful than those already in existence.
正式开启与该行星联系的计划
They developed a program to get in contact with this distant planet.
命名为灯塔计划
The program was known as "Project Beacon".
灯塔计划  喜马拉雅山
今天将展开前所未有的
NOGRADY: Today really marks the first stage
科技大跃进的第一阶段
of an unprecedented technological advancement.
我们陆续发现了所谓在适居带的行星
We have begun to identify so-called Goldilocks planets.
这些行星与各自星系大阳的关系
These are planets that share a similar relationship with their sun
和我们类似
as we have with ours.
行星距离太阳太远，会太冷
If a planet's too far away from its sun, it's too cold.
靠得太近，则会太热
If it's too close to its sun, it's too hot.
而类地球行星，距离就刚好
But for an Earth-like planet, the distance is just right.
可能非常适合生命的延续
Potentially perfect for sustaining life.
我们终于找到一颗行星
We have finally managed to identify one planet
与自身的太阳距离刚好
that is the right distance
液态水得以存在
from its star to hold water
质量也够大，能够保有大气层
and is the right mass to sustain an atmosphere.
每24小时，我们夏威夷的基地
Every 24 hours, our station in Hawaii
会发送讯号到在轨道上的L7卫星
will transmit a signal to Landsat 7, our deep orbiting satellite,
卫星增强讯号后再传递至目标星球
which will amplify and relay the signal to our targeted planet
我们特别慎重其事的称它为G星球
which is, rather grandly, entitled Planet G.
如果真的有外星智慧生物来到这里
If there is intelligent life out there, and they come here
就会像哥伦布与印第安人
it's going to be like Columbus and the lndians.
只不过，我们会是印第安人
Only, we're the lndians.
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen,
请准备见证历史
please prepare to bear witness to the making of history.
开始传送
Start transmission.
夏威夷   欧胡岛
美国太空总署
就在我们这里设立基地
JACKlE: It seems as though NASA is setting up shop right here in our own backyard.
今天，灯塔计划正式展开
Today, the Beacon International Project was launched.
欧胡岛上的卫星设备
Satellite dishes here on Oahu
强力传送讯号至外太空
sending out very powerful signals into deep space
希望能与可能存在的
with an attempt to communicate with anyone...
再来一轮，寿星
STONE: Another round, birthday boy.
任何生物联系
JACKlE:...or anything that might be out there listening.
我要敬你酒
A toast.
老弟，生日快乐
Happy birthday, little brother.
祝你健康快乐，心想事成
I'm wishing you success and growth, and happiness.
今年顺顺利利的
May this be a great year for you.
一定会顺利的
It's going to be a great year.
我爱你一我也爱你
I love you. I love you, too.
依照哈波家的惯例
So, in the great Hopper family tradition,
今年我要送你约翰伍登教练的名言
this year I'm quoting from Coach John Wooden.
约翰
Johnny.
“逆境让我们…，
"Adversity is the state in which man
“更能够认识自己”
"most easily becomes acquainted with himself
“尤其是周遭的人都不看好的时候”
"being especially free of admirers then."
干杯
Cheers.
我才不要
I'm not cheers-ing that.
这对你很受用
It's a very good quote for you.
周遭的人都不看好  但我还有机会？
"l may be free of admirers right now but there is still time"?
你闭嘴好吗？
Will you shut up?
点蜡烛，举杯
Light your cupcake and raise your glass.
这是你买的？
Did you get me that?
对，我买给你的
Yes, I got you that.
谢谢，真的好贴心
Thank you, that's very sweet.
不客气，你大客气了
You're welcome. You're very welcome.
我认识一个叫东尼的
I got this guy, Tony.
他说他可以安排你到工地上班
He said he can get you a construction job.
你只要打电话给他就行了
All you need to do is call him.
我要啤酒和鸡肉卷饼
Could I get a beer and a chicken burrito, please?
对不起，厨房休息了
Sorry, kitchen's closed.
你不会打给他，对吧
STONE: You're not going to call him, are you?
帮我谢谢东尼
Give Tony my best,
但我不需要你们帮我拢工作
but I don't need you or Tony's help, for that matter.
你不打给他，就跟我去当海军
You can call him or join me in the Navy.
不要 -好吧，算了
No. Great. All right.
生日快乐，吹蜡烛许愿吧
Happy birthday. Blow out your candle and make a wish.
别把愿望浪费在女孩身上
Do not waste a wish on a girl.
许个新工作、房子
Wish for a job, an apartment.
或是新车，我就不用每次都载你
A new alternator belt, so I don't have to drive you everywhere.
还有工作  -你说了两次“工作
A job, or... You said "job" twice.
是我过生日，是我的愿望
It's my birthday and my wish.
可以吗？
All right?
拜托别浪费它
Please don't waste it.
你浪费掉了，对吧
You just wasted that wish, didn't you?
我要出动了 -你不会吧
I'm going in. You're not going in.
我看起来如何？
How do I look?
等等，我帮你调一下
Wait, let me just fix that.
帅呆了 !
Awesome!
好了，公主，去迷倒她们吧
All right, princess, go get 'em.
真是好的开始
Great start.  Ugh.
有什么问题吗？
What seems to be the problem?
我要鸡肉卷饼
I want a chicken burrito.
强尼，快给她鸡肉卷饼
Johnny, chicken burrito her.
休想  -给她鸡肉卷饼
BARTENDER: It ain't happening. Chicken burrito her.
哈波，厨房休息了
Kitchen's closed, Hopper.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
我饿了
I'm hungry.
你才不叫“饿了’
That's not your name.
给我五分钟
If you give me five minutes
我会变出鸡肉卷饼
I will get you your chicken burrito.
五分钟，计时开始
Five minutes, starting now.
鸡肉卷饼时间，我要闪了
(BELCHES) Chicken burrito time, I'm out.
鸡肉卷饼，收到
Chicken burrito, roger that.
等一下
HOPPER: Wait! Hi!
不！帮个忙
No! Let's just...
拜托再开个门就好
Just one twist of the key and we will be good.
你好吗？
How are you, ma'am?
你好吗？还有鸡肉卷饼耶
How you doing? Burritos, right there.
打烊了，下次请早，老兄
It's closed. Too late, pal.
好吧
Okay.
就在那里，拜托啦
It's right there. Please?
现在也不是吃卷饼的时候，会变胖
It's too late to eat a burrito. Too many complex carbs.
3块9毛9
$3.99...
鸡肉…卷饼…
(GRUNTlNG) Chicken burrito.
我拿到了！
I got it!
不要跑！
Hey! Freeze!
我拿到你要的卷饼了！
I got a burrito! I got it!
不准动！
Freeze!
躺着别动！
(GASPS) Stay down!
他又要爬起来了！
MAN: He's getting back up!
我受够了！你看你自己！
STONE: I've had it! Look at yourself!
怎么老是惹事生非？
How is it that you screw everything up?
对了，你昨晚想把的女孩
By the way, that girl you were trying to impress last night,
你知道她父亲是谁吗？
do you know who her father is?
舰队司令史恩！
Admiral Shane!
整个舰队都归他管！
He runs the whole damn fleet!
所以，你连我的工作和人生也搞砸！
So, now you're messing with my job. My life!
你认识那个女的？
You know that girl?
卷饼女？
The burrito girl?
我一向都不插手你的事吧
I've always stayed out ofyour business, haven't l?
因为我希望总有一天你会学乖
Because I was hoping that maybe one day you would learn from your mistakes.
你会长大、成熟
You would grow up, you would mature a bit!
我的背还好吧？
Is my back all right?
天阿！我的背！
Oh, my God! My back!
你26岁了，做了什么？
You're 26, and what have you got? You got, what?
存款剩65块？
Sixty-five dollars to your name?
我被电击枪射
I got tazed.
一辆坏的车子，睡我家沙发！
A car that doesn't start. You're living on my couch!
那玩意儿真的有用！
Those things work!
看看你自己
Man, look at yourself.
我的天啊！
Oh, my God.
从现在开始
As from now,
这一秒开始，该过新生活了
as from right this second, there is a new dynamic at play.
新生活守则如下
And this dynamic is the following.
现在开始，一切我说了算，不准顶嘴
From here on, until I state otherwise, there will be no more debate,
不用讨论，没有折衷方案！
no more discussion, no more compromise!
我说话，你就听，我命令，你就做
It's me speaking, you listening. Me saying, you doing.
你懂吗？
Do you understand that?
该是重新开始的时候了
It's time for a new course of action.
新方向
A new direction.
重新做人
A game change.
你要跟我去当海军
You are joining me in the Navy.
这里是夏威夷本地新闻
ANNOUNCER: Live, local, this is Hawaii News Now.
夏威夷正如火如荼展开
Thousands of sailors on dozens of ships
环太平洋海军军演
are coming to Hawaii for RIMPAC.
这是全球规模最大的跨国海军演习
NEWSCASTER 1 : RIMPAC is the world's largest multinational maritime exercise.
有14国参与
NEWSCASTER 2: RIMPAC is a military ballet of 14 navies...
参演兵力两万人
NEWSCASTER 3: 20,000 Navy personnel.
目的是增进各国之间的合作
Cooperation and collaboration amongst the countries is the goal.
与关系的建立
NEWSCASTER 3: Relationship-building is the key.
但行动并不只限于海上
NEWSCASTER 4: Not all the action is taking place out on the water.
在陆地上也将有体育项目竞赛
There will also be sporting events here on land.
别管世界杯了，这是环太杯足球决赛
Forget World Cup, this is the RIMPAC Cup final.
今天的夏威夷，天气晴朗依旧
ANNOUNCER 1 : It's another beautiful day here in Hawaii, as usual.
但在球场上，腥风血雨正展开
ANNOUNCER 2: Indeed it is, but a storm is brewing on the field
散乱的美国队与日本队硬碰硬
as the scrappy U.S.A. team is butting heads with Japan.
日本队以2比0领先
The score is 2-nil, Japan.
美国队一直苦苦追赶
The U.S. has been trailing all day.
队长艾历斯哈波得设法力挽狂澜
Team leader Alex Hopper has got to do something to rally the troops here.
加油
Turn it up!
这球救得好！
ANNOUNCER 1 : Big save! Great save!
救得好！史东哈波今天表现优异
ANNOUNCER 2: Big save! Stone Hopper, he's answered every test today.
你是怎样，太夸张了吧？
What's wrong with you, drama queen?
起来吧，小公王！
Get up, princess, come on!
美国队欧弟传球给6号艾伦
ANNOUNCER 1: U.S.A. 's Ordy squares the ball over to number 6, Alan.
克利佛用脚跟妙传
ANNOUNCER 2: Clever backheel into space...
哈波射门得分！
ANNOUNCER 1: Hopper... Goal!
像飞弹般飞过岩代
A missile, past Iwashiro.
美国队终于有起死回生的迹象
The U.S. is finally on the board, showing some signs of life
比数2比1，日本队领先
with the score, 2-1, Japan.
现在是伤停时闻，美国队能追平吗？
ANNOUNCER 2: We are now into stoppage time. Can the U.S. tie it up?
还有多少时闲？
Time! Time! Time!
一分钟
One minute left.
艾历斯，球来了！
Alex, it's coming your way!
史东哈波传球位置冶到好处
ANNOUNCER 1: Stone Hopper has placed it perfectly.
球落点非常好
It takes a fortuitous bounce.
哈波没有越位
Hopper is underneath it and on-side.
主裁判！
Hey, ref! (WHlSTLE BLOWlNG)
美国队被给予一次点球机会
ANNOUNCER 1 : A penalty kick has been awarded to the United States.
永田和哈波在禁区里发生碰撞
Nagata made contact with Hopper inside the box.
所谓碰撞是指永田一脚踢在哈波脸上
ANNOUNCER 2: And by "contact, " you mean Nagata kicked him in the face.
你没事吧？ -我没事
STONE: You all right?   Yeah, I'm fine.
史东走向艾历斯
ANNOUNCER 1: Stone Hopper has come up the field.
我很好，不用你帮忙
I'm fine. I don't need your help.
布朗森会踢罚球
Bronson is going to take it.
布朗森！
Bronson!
干嘛叫布朗森？不，不行
What do you mean, "Bronson"? No, negative.
布朗森，你来罚球
I'm fine. Bronson, you're gonna take this.
布朗森，不要动 -布朗森，过来
Bronson, don't move. Bronson, come here.
你再走一步，你就死定了！
Bronson, you move one more step, you're dead!
你今天想死吗？想死吗？
Do you want to die today? Do you want to die?
明智的选择
Good choice.
他一定是脑震荡了
He is definitely concussed.
你在威胁我的水手
You just threatened one of my sailors.
看来是艾历斯哈波要罚球
ANNOUNCER 1: Looks like it's going to be his little brother, Alex Hopper.
如果我是史东，我会选别人
ANNOUNCER 2: If I was Stone, I would have picked another shooter.
我不认为他被踢到还会没事
I'm skeptical that Hopper is 100 percent.
专心，专心，我做得到的
Engage, engage. Impose will, impose will.
白痴有两种，哈波
There are two kinds of idiots, Hopper.
一种看踢球的方向
One looks where he kicks,
一种看别的地方
the other looks where he doesn't kick.
你是哪一种白痴？
Which idiot are you?
我是踢烂守门员脸的那种
I'm the idiot that's going to kick it through your keeper's face.
准备好踢延长赛吧
Get ready for overtime.
大家都看着哈波
ANNOUNCER 2: All eyes on Hopper.
他可能让比赛进入延长赛
He could send this into overtime.
开始了
(BLOWlNG WHlSTLE) ANNOUNCER 1: And here we go.
如果哈波进球，美国队就进入延长赛
If Hopper scores, the U.S. will go into overtime.
一颗高射炮，连横梁都没碰着
Oh! ANNOUNCER 1: Hopper sails one miles over the crossbar, nowhere near the goal.
果然是这样
Typical.
美国队真令人失望
ANNOUNCER 2: What a heartbreak for the U.S.
带伤上阵的艾历斯哈波踢得太差了
ANNOUNCER 1 : It was a very poor attempt by the obviously injured Alex Hopper.
他拒绝退场
He refused to come out of the game
太过固执而使美国队输掉比赛
and his stubbornness cost the United States.
恭喜日本队赢得2012环太杯冠军
Congratulations to Japan, our 2012 RIMPAC Cup winners.
最后比数
The final, as we sign off,
日本胜美国，2比1
Japan, 2. The United States, 1.
准备好了吗？ -好了
Are you ready for this? Born.
你确定？
Are you sure?
从没这么笃定过
Never been more sure of anything in my life.
你打算说什么？
What are you going to say?
我要像个男人勇敢的走过去
I'm going to walk up to him, man to man,
直盯着他的眼睛
and look him straight in the eyes.
说什么呢？
With what words?
我想说的
My words.
好吧
Okay. (CLEARS THROAT)
“长官…”
"Sir...
“您的女儿是我此生最棒的际遇”
"Your daughter is the best thing that has ever happened to me.
“她聪明、仁慈、美丽、有趣”
"She's smart, kind, beautiful, funny,
“我疯狂地爱着她”
"and I'm madly in love with her.
“如您允许我娶她，
"lt would be an honor
“将是我莫大荣幸”
to have your permission to marry her."
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
美国海军密苏里号  绰号‘莫老大”
欢迎各位参加环大平洋海军演习
First off, I'd like to welcome you all to the RIMPAC International Naval War Games.
也欢迎各位登上美国海军史上
And I'd like to welcome you onboard
最伟大的战舰
the greatest fighting ship in American naval history.
“莫老大”，密苏里号
The "Mighty Mo, " the U.S.S. Missouri.
糟了！
Shit!
哈波，你的帽子
Hopper, your cover.
我故意要你提醒的
I'm keeping you on your toes.
走了，快点，哈波
Hopper, let's go, come on. Hopper!
这边
HOPPER: This way.
不，走错了
No, no, no.
长官，这边
GUARD: That way, sir.
对，我知道
HOPPER: Yes, yes, I knew that.
你看起来真美
We knew that. You look good.
密苏里号是美军建造的最后一艘战列舰
The U.S.S. Missouri was the final battleship to be completed by the United States
后来才被更先进的舰队取代而退役
before being de-commissioned and replaced with a more modern fleet of vessels,
如驱逐舰
Like destroyers.
战列舰跟驱逐舰有什么不一样？
What's the difference between a battleship and a destroyer?
战列舰是很棒的船
Battleships are great ships.
但有点像恐龙
But they are kind of like dinosaurs.
可以抵挡攻击，像拳击沙袋一样
They're designed to take hits, like a floating punching bag.
可是驱逐舰就超赞的
But then there's destroyers, which are just awesome.
可以像魔鬼终结者一样猛攻
They're designed to dish it out like the Terminator.
你是舰长吗？
Are you a Captain?
他不是，舰长才不会迟到，走吧
No, he's not a Captain because he's always late. Come on.
我比船还猛
I fight the ship.
所以更赞
Which is even better.
听我说，搞定他
Listen, get it done. Get it done.
宝贝，只是形式罢了，我搞得定
Babe, it's a formality.
好，快去吧
Okay, go. I'm all over it.
今天的来宾是密苏里号的退役军人
We have with us today, veterans from the Missouri
有些人甚至从二次大战就在此服役
who have served on her, some going back to World War II.
他们是海军最优良的典范
Examples of the finest men to have ever served in any navy.
哈波上尉，真荣幸你可以加入
Lieutenant Hopper, what an honor. Thank you for joining us.
很高兴来这里
Good to be here.
在准备进行这次盛大演习之际
And now, as we prepare to embark on this outstanding exercise...
我很紧张  -墨镜拿掉
I'm nervous. Shades off.
我要请几位舰长上台
I would like the Commanding Officers to come to the stage.
日本的永田舰长
Captain Nagata, Japan.
马来西亚的路舰长
Captain Lou, Malaysia.
阿罗，阿罗
(GREETlNG lN MALAY)
发音跟我们很像
It's so close to the way we say it.
他讨厌我
He hates me.
他不讨厌你，闭嘴
He doesn't hate you. Shut up. Shut up.
澳洲的杰克斯舰长
SHANE: Captain Jacks, Australia.
尬呆《您好》  -闭嘴
G'day. Shut up.
尬呆！
G'day!
闭嘴  -尬呆
Shut up. G'day.
特别介绍美国海军史东哈波中校
A special acknowledgment to Commander Stone Hopper, United States Navy.
该你了，迷死他们
Go, that's your call. Knock 'em out.
他带领的官兵和战舰
Who, along with his outstanding crew and ship,
是去年演习评分最高的
had the highest overall rating last year.
墨镜拿掉，哈波
Shades off, Hopper.
中校
Commander.
谢谢你，司令
Thank you, Admiral.
欢迎各位，今天很高兴看到大家
Welcome, everybody. It's really great to see you all here today.
尤其是各位前辈，真的很荣幸
Especially you, gentlemen. It's a true honor.
今年，我和弟兄们更将小心翼翼
Me and my crew, we're going to have to be on our toes this year
因为在座各位都蓄势待发
because your ships look outstanding and your men look ready.
祝大家军演顺利
So, good luck out there.
注意安全，勇往直前
Be safe and keep charging.
他爱他女儿，而她爱你
He loves his daughter, she loves you.
他会尊重她的决定
He's going to respect that.
麦克  -司令
Hey, Mike. Admiral.
你记得珊珊吧？
You remember Sam?
这真是个过时的传统
It's an obsolete tradition, this asking for permission.
都什么时代了  -闭嘴
Tell me where this came from. Stop.
珊珊现在是物理治疗师了
Sam's a physical therapist now.
别乱想，快过去做该做的事
Stop worrying about this and walk up and do what you got to do.
哈罗，哈波
Hello, Hopper.
你在这干嘛？
Why are you here?
有好戏看了
This is going to be sweet.
我没犯规   -是吗？
I was within the rules. Really?
踢我的脸不算犯规？
Were you in the rules when you kicked me in the face?
你现在应该有更重要的事要做吧？
Isn't there something more important you should be doing right now?
他超讨厌那个人
He hates the man.
这样有点幼稚吧
That seems a bit juvenile, wouldn't you say?
你可以试着去惹他啊
Go mess with him and see what happens.
为什么？  -去啊
Why? CORA: Do it.
让我揍你，看你还会不会笑
Would it be funny if I punched you in the face?
笑屁啊？ -够了
Would that be funny? Stop it.
你就像是肯德基里的弱鸡
Chicken. Kentucky Fried Chicken.
对啊，我超爱4号餐的
Yeah, I love it. A two-piece meal.
其实你蛮像肯德基爷爷的
You look like Colonel Sanders, actually.
他很帅啊
He was a handsome man.
你好棒，爹地
Good job out there, Dad.
你想干嘛？
What do you want?
哈波想要五分钟时间跟你谈谈
Hopper needs five minutes of your time.
够了  -什么意思？
That's enough. What do you mean?
你现在应该有更重要的事要做吧？
Don't you have something more important you should be doing right now?
最多三分钟
Three minutes, tops.
谢谢，我爱你
Thank you. I love you. Thank you, Daddy.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
他会打烂我的脸  - 他才不会
He's going to smash my face in.  He's not going to smash your face in.
天啊
Oh, my God.
长官，是我的荣幸
Sir, it would be an honor.
长官长官长官
Sir. Sir. Sir.
您的允许是我的荣幸
Give me your permission. It would be an honor to have your permission.
长官，给我允许，怎么样？
Sir, give me your permission. What's your deal?
我很感恩
It would be a thankful honor
能得到您的允许来荣耀您的手
to have your permission to honor your hand.
什么鬼东西
What?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
长官
Sir,
我可以娶您的女儿吗？
may I please marry your daughter?
她是我的一切
She's everything I have,
我爱她
and I love her.
自言自语啊，哈波先生？
Talking to yourself, Mr. Hopper?
对啊
Yeah, I was.
我其实是在讲你
I was actually talking about you, Nagata.
长官，这完全是意外，厕所地板太湿
Sir, it was a fluke accident. The bathroom floor was wet.
我滑倒
I began to fall.
永田舰长好心来扶我
Captain Nagata kindly reached out to help.
我们的头互撞
YUGl: Our heads go bang.
我们跌倒，砰，又撞到
We fall back. Bang, again.
就像伟大的裘利路易
Just like the great Jerry Lewis.
裘利路易
Jerry Lewis?
他刚刚说裘利路易
Did he just say "Jerry Lewis"?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
你在开玩笑吗？
BROWLEY: Are you kidding me?
“门房小弟”还有“神经教授”
The Bellboy and original The Nutty Professor.
都是很好看的电影
Very good movies.
他还是个很出色的人道主义者
He is a great humanitarian, sir.
你们两个以为可以开玩笑
You both think this is a joke
就错得大离谱了
and you are very much mistaken.
这种事不准再发生，听清楚了吗？
This will not happen again. Do I make myself clear?
是，长官
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
让我和哈波单独讲几句话
Gentlemen, give me a minute with Mr. Hopper, here.
你到底是怎么了？
What is wrong with you?
你天资过人却都白白浪费了
You've got skills, but I have never ever seen a man waste them like you.
“选绎避开巨浪，或者
"Keep the ship out of the surf and spray..."
航向里毁灭一途”
"...or you will plunge to destruction."
荷马诗篇，长官
Homer, sir.
你明知故犯只会让我更生气
The fact that you know that infuriates me beyond words.
我女儿到底看上你哪一点
What my daughter sees in you is a great mystery to me.
你很聪明
You are a very smart individual
但个性冲动，缺乏判断和领导能力
with very weak character, leadership and decision-making skills.
你有没有什么话要说？
Do you have anything to say to me? Anything?
报告长官，没有
Negative, sir.
好好好享受这次海军演习
Enjoy these naval exercises, Hopper.
这也许会是你最后一次了
They are likely to be your last.
解散
Dismissed.
我能帮上忙吗？
WALTER: Is there anything I can do to help?
不能
Negative.
如果你想谈谈……  -我不想
If you want to talk about anything... I don't.
如果你改变主意… - 我不会
If you change your mind... I won't.
收到
Roger that.
环太军演夏威夷檀香山第一夭
Contact DESRON ONE. Commence anti-submarine warfare exercises.
“信守上帝，掌控万物”
Commence air operations.
美国海军航母  雷根号
联络第一驱逐舰队
开始反潜战略演习
开始空战演习
美国海军驱逐舰桑普森号
午安，桑普森号
Good afternoon, Sampson.
欢迎参加第一天的演习
Welcome to Day One of the RIMPAC naval war games.
我们要加强团队技能
We are here to sharpen our skills as a team.
美国海军驱逐舰JPJ号
身为各位的武器作业军官
HOPPER: As your weapons officer,
容我提醒，这是艘交战船舰
Let me remind you that this is a combat vessel
我们要展现出卓越的领导与操控技能
and we will excel in our command and control.
我要大家随时提高警觉
STONE: I want everyone to stay frosty.
13国友军近在咫尺
We're going to be close-maneuvering with 13 nations out here.
我们要干掉所有的船
We are here to crush every other ship.
我期待大家能学到很多
I'm excited to see what we learn.
我们不是来这里学习的
We are not here in this weapons room to learn.
注意安全，互相照顾，勇往直前
Be safe out there, look out for each other and keep charging.
回到珍珠港前
If we return to Pearl
要是表现比别人差
without having outperformed every other ship on that ocean,I will personally...
喂，桑德斯，我们怎么会被
Yo, Saunders, we've ended up in a department
川普和泰森的合体怪物
run by some kind of Donald Trump/Mike Tyson mutant combo.
你说什么，蕾支丝士官？
What was that, Petty Officer Raikes?
没什么，长官
CORA: Nothing, sir.
我听到你说川普，要不要说明一下？
I swear you said, "Donald Trump." Want to clarify?
我还听到泰森
I think I heard a "Mike Tyson," as well.
我只是觉得你和他们一样
If you did, it was only in reference to the fact
散发着耀眼的冲劲与智慧
that you both project great physical intensity, sir.
真会拍马屁
That's flattering.
哈波！有直升机会去桑普森号
Hopper! There's a helo headed for the Sampson.
你给我上去
Make sure your ass is on it.
为什么？我不知道！
Why? I don't know why!
坐上去就是了
Just make sure you're on it!
收到长官
Copy, sir.
有够衰
Damn.
这是天14，请清空甲板，返航中
PlLOT: Scorpion one four, clear our deck. En route with parts and techs.
确认乘客：哈波上尉
OFFlCER: Confirm Lieutenant Hopper en route.
我刚跟海军法庭通完电话
STONE: I just got off the phone with the JAG.
然后呢？
And?
你可能会被除名
They are probably going to kick you out of the Navy.
什么时候？
When?
我们回去那天
The day we get back.
军演结束后？ - 对
From RlMPAC? Yeah.
你得打电话，拉点关系，你要
You have got to make some calls. There has got to be...
我要找谁来教你谦逊？
Who do I call to teach you humility?
对不起，我不知道
I am sorry, I don't have that number.
我就是搞不懂
I just don't get it, man.
你明明很有潜力
You have got so much potential.
很抱歉你要面对这些
I'm sorry you have to deal with this.
很抱歉让你失望了
And I am sorry I let you down.
夏威夷欧胡岛海军复健中心
身体站直
MAN: Stand up nice and tall.
注意看绿色标记，就在你的背中间
I want you to focus on that green marker,right in the middle of your back.
你以为我一直在干嘛？
MlCK: What do you think I'm paying attention to?
两脚并拢
MAN: Keep your feet together.
我没办法再并拢了
My feet can't get any closer.
站直  - 我受够了
Stand up tall. All right. I had enough of this.
继续，再一下就好
Keep going. Just a little bit more.
他妈的关掉！
Turn the damned thing off!  Come on. We're just about there.
快到了  - 马上关掉！
Turn it off now!
我是你新的复健师
I'm your new physical therapist.
我感受到你的极度愤怒
I am sensing a lot of anger.
感觉还真敏锐
Very perceptive of you.
还有别的情绪吗，米克？
Is there anything besides anger in there, Mick?
没什么
Not much.
上一位复健师说你失去奋斗意志
Your last therapist says that you lost the will to fight.
是这样吗？
Is that accurate?
腿都没了要怎么奋斗
I lost my fight when I lost my legs.
你还是那个22岁就赢得金手套的人
Do you realize you're still the same man that won the Golden Gloves at 22?
获颁阿富汗战争铜星勋章的也是你
A Bronze Star in Afghanistan? The same man.
我不是个完整的人
I am half a man.
不完整就当不了兵
And half a man ain't enough to be a soldier.
我只知道怎么当军人
That's all I have ever known.
那好，走吧
All right. Let's go.
我们去散散步
We are going to take a walk.
我不要
No, we are not.
把义肢穿上
Legs on.
你不想爬山，但还蛮会爬的嘛
SAM: You're doing pretty good for a guy who doesn't want to be hiking.
这种山连我的狗芥末都可以爬
My dog, Mustard, could climb this mountain.
好极了，你和芥未可以再一起来
Great, you and Mustard can go and make some memories on Mauna Kea.
会很好玩
Sounds like fun.
芥末被卡车撞死了
Mustard's dead. Mustard got hit by a dump truck.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我早就释怀了
I'm over it.
我以为你那里已经没讯号了
Hey. I thought you would be out of range by now.
我还有大约五分钟时间
HOPPER: I have around five minutes of left time.
怎么样？ - 还好
SAM: How is it?  It's fine.
对不起我搞砸了
I'm sorry. I messed up.
我一回去就马上再跟你父亲谈
And I'm going to talk to your father as soon as I get back.
别再搞砸了，好吗？
Stop messing things up, okay?
收到，我爱你
Copy that. I love you.
我爱你
I love you.
怎么了，帕克？ - 你看这个
NOGRADY: What is it, Parker? Take a look at this.
“侦测到五个物体接近中”
(BEEPlNG RAPlDLY)
开玩笑的吧
Nice one. It's a joke, right?
应该不是
I don't think so.
天啊
My God.
夏威夷马鞍岭信号站
(HUMMlNG) (THE BLUE DANUBE PLAYlNG ON HEADPHONES)
卡尔
Cal.
卡尔！
Cal! Huh?
雷达侦测到奇怪的讯号
Got some weird activity on all the radar screens.
奇怪？
Weird?
真的，非常奇怪
Yeah, man. Really weird.
对了，诺奎帝博士来电
Mmm-hmm.Oh, uh, Dr. Nogrady is on the phone for you, too.
这才叫奇怪，诺奎帝博士，真的吗？
That is weird. Seriously, Dr. Nogrady?
这种事下次请先讲好不好？
Lead with that next time. Okay, Danny?
凡事总有轻重缓急
You got to start prioritizing your information.
最重要的事一定要先讲，懂吗?
If you have to tell me "1, 2, 3," you don't start with "M."  You know what I mean?
我不是在骂你笨
I mean, I'm not saying that you are a boob,
但这真的很蠢
but this is boob-ish behavior.
诺奎帝博士，你好
Hi, Dr. Nogrady.
你看到了吗？
Are you seeing what I am seeing?
接近的物体轨迹 - 没错
The incoming tracks.  Correct.
五个清楚的物体
I've got five distinct objects...
五个以整齐队形移动的物体
Five distinct objects that are moving in formation.
它们锁住了我的讯号，直冲向我这里
They are locked in on my signal. They are headed straight for me.
没错
Correct.
或许我们该通知大空总署
Maybe we should call NASA.
太空总署已经打来了，他们在线上
NASA have called us. They're on the phone right now.
早安，札帕塔先生
Good morning, Mr. Zapata.
你们是大空总署？
NASA?
我们正在追踪从主体剥离的物件
We are tracking something splintering off of the main group.
那不是剥离，它要散了
That's not splitting off. That thing is breaking apart.
有人联络中国吗？因为这绝不是陨石
Has anyone called the Chinese? Because this is no meteor.
确认过了，不是俄国也不是中国的
Yes, we have checked. It's not the Russians, it's not the Chinese.
也许我们应该叫空军准备出动战机
Maybe we should call the Air Force,because they might want to fuel up their jets.
空军也在线上
NOGRADY: The Air Force is online.
既然这些东西正朝你的方向过去
It appears the event is headed your way.
你要准备好
Prepare yourself.
知道了，但我该怎么准备？
Roger that. How would you suggest that I prepare myself, sir?
撑着点
Brace.
中国香港
大家请坐
MAN 1 : Let's all be seated.
有人可以解释发生什么事吗？
I am hoping somebody here can explain this to me.
部长，这物体有四块掉在大平洋
CHAlRMAN: Mr. Secretary, four of the five objects landed in the Pacific Ocean.
脱离主体的第五块
The fifth one appeared to have broken apart
猛烈撞击香港
making significant contact with Hong Kong,
其他地方像苏格兰
but other places were also affected.
德国、法国甚至爱荷华都受到波及
Scotland, Germany, France, even lowa.
这究竟是什么东西？
So, what is it?
目前我们有几种推测
Sir, at this point we are working on a couple of theories.
这位是？
And you are who, sir?
我是大空总署的人
I am with NASA.
大空总署来干嘛？
What is NASA present in this room for?
我们几乎可以确定
NASA DlRECTOR: We are looking at the very real possibility
这次是货真价实的外星人事件
that this is legitimate extraterrestrial contact.
资料显示异物是从葛利斯大阳系来的
It appears that it originated from the Gliese solar system.
G星球的故乡
Home of Planet G.
你是说我们送出讯号后
You are saying that we sent out a signal
外星人现在回call?
and we got back an alien response?
长官，我们刚收到珍珠港传来的消息
WATCH OFFlCER: Sir, we just got word from Pearl.
他们认为撞击香港的物体
They believe whatever made impact with Hong Kong,
也有部分坠落在大平洋
has also made impact with the Pacific Ocean.
大平洋的哪里？
Where in the Pacific?
大概在我们南方150里处
Approximately 150 miles south of where we are right now, sir.
应该就在那边，但雷达没有显示
It should be right there, but we are not seeing anything.
帮我接桑普森号
Get me the Sampson. Yes, sir.
航向2-2-0，速度25节
Base course, 2-2-0. Speed, 25.
舰长
我们接到命令要进入一号队形
舰长请到舰桥！
BRlDGE OFFlCER: Captain on the bridge!
伤亡人数仍在统计中
As casualty reports come in,
目前还不知道撞击香港的物体为何
it's still unclear exactly what it was that hit Hong Kong.
那东西不是来自地球的
It isn't anything from this planet.
我们怎么知道？
How do we know that?
因为中国已经抽验过了
Because the Chinese have sampled it.
它的成分根本不在元素周期表上
It's made of a material that does not exist in the periodic table.
这不是地球的玩意儿
It's literally not of this Earth.
唯一能确认的是铹元素
The only element they've been able to identify is lawrencium.
铹？
Lawrencium?
别抖脚了
You got to stop tapping.
你抖得比我还厉害
You're tapping. You're the loud one.
看它的纹路，有点像
NOGRADY: Looking at the grid patterns,it's something in the neighborhood
太阳能板或通讯介面
of solar paneling or communications paneling.
可能是某种通讯装置
It may be some kind of a communication unit.
通讯？
Communications?
谁在通讯？跟谁通讯？
Who is communicating what? To who?
那是什么鬼东西？
JlMMY: What the heck is that?
舰桥，这里是右舷t望站
Bridge, starboard lookout. I've got an unknown surface contact.
方位232有不明物体，距离8千码
Bearing is 2-3-2 true, approximately 8,000 yards.
长官？
Sir?
怎么？
STONE: Yeah.
你最好过来看一下
You may want to come take a look at this.
我正在看
I am looking at it, Mr. Strodell.
在雷达上，长官
On the radar, sir.
很奇怪的事
Something very peculiar.
那是JPJ号吧？
STONE: That's the John Paul Jones, right?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
这是妙高号？ - 是的
The Myoko? Yes, sir, it is.
为什么我看不到
So, why don't I see...
那个东西？
See that?
作战情报中心，这是舰长
Combat, Captain.
我可以目视目标在237水面上
I have a visual on the track bearing 2-3-7 on the horizon.
你那边有什么资讯？
What do you hold in that bearing?
舰桥，战略官报告，237没有警示
Bridge, TAO. I've got nothing at 2-3-7.
我看得很清楚，把它找出来
I'm looking right at it, Mr. Hopper. Find me something.
显控台，有什么发现？ - 确认中
Scope, 2-3-7, what do you got? Stand by.
报告长官，没有发现
That's negative, sir. Scope's clear, I got nothing.
泰勒，你是不是弄坏了？
Taylor, did you break this son-of-a-bitch?
没有，长官，我没有弄坏
No, I didn't do anything to it, sir.
你知道我可是会把你丢下船的
You know I will throw your ass off this ship.
报告长官，我知道
I know you will, sir.
长官，摄录机拍到了
Got it, sir. On my camera.
是什么？
What is it?
我不知道
I don't know.
这是演习的一部分吗？
Is this some kind of exercise?
有可能
Probably.
位于北纬 15°37′
Unknown vessel in the vicinity of 1-5 degrees, 3-7 minutes north,
西经159°33′的
and 1-5-9 degrees, 3-3 minutes west.
不明船舰
Request you establish communications
请用VHF16频道与我方通讯
with my vessel on VHF channel 16,
请表明身分，完毕
and identify yourself, over.
JPJ号，我是桑普森号舰长
John Paul Jones, this is Sampson, Charlie Oscar.
我是JPJ号舰长
John Paul Jones, Charlie Oscar.
请派遣一个小队去看看到底怎么回事
I would like you to send a team over and take a closer look.
没问题，我们立刻派出侦查小组
No problem. We will get a team in the water right away.
收到
Roger.
大家提高警觉，情况很诡异
I'll tell you what, boys, this is a head-stumper.
这是什么？
WALTER: What is it?
货物？中国搞的鬼？
Lost cargo? Chinese?
我不知道
I don't know.
难道是游艇？还是卫星？
Yacht? Satellite?
野兽，我五秒前不知道
Beast, I didn't know five seconds ago,
现在还是不知道
and I don't know now.
这是美国海军战舰JPJ号
This is the U.S. Navy warship John Paul Jones.
听到请回答
I'm attempting to communicate with you.
准备让我方登船
Prepare to be boarded.
你看过这种东西吗？
You ever seen anything like this?
没有
No.
真诡异
It's weird, man.
上尉！我有不好的预感
LT! I don't think that's a good idea.
知道了，老大
Got it, chief.
真的不太好，上尉
Real bad idea, Lieutenant.
靠！快点，蕾克丝
Oh, shit. Move it, Raikes!
上尉！ - 上尉，起来！
WALTER: LT! Lieutenant, get up!
上尉！
Lieutenant!  Whoa, whoa, whoa!
长官
Sir!
联络桑普森号
Get me the Sampson.
桑普森号，这里是AB
WATCH OFFlCER: Alpha Bravo. Sampson, this is Alpha Bravo.
长官，我们联络不上桑普森号
Sir, we're unable to contact the Sampson.
雷根号，这里是野骑404
Reagan control, this is Rough Rider 4-0-4.
我遭遇到强烈乱流
I'm encountering some severe...
野骑404请回答，是否收到？
Rough Rider 4-0-4, come in. Do you copy?
进入1号作战状态
Put the force at weapons posture one.
红色警戒
Warning red,
确认敌意
weapons tight.
全面备战
I want everything loaded.
舰桥，发生什么事？
OFFlCER: Bridge, what's happened?
雷达完全失效了，长官
My radar's totally down, sir.
和基地也失联，通讯全断了
EXECUTlVE OFFlCER: We've lost contact with base. All comms are offline.
一定是北韩在搞鬼，相信我
It's the North Koreans, I'm telling you.
你没事吧？上尉？
Hey, Lieutenant, you good?
听到了吗？加油！
Come on, you with me?
快点，妈的！
Come on. Damn it!
加油！清醒没？
Come on! Squared away?
醒了
I'm squared away.
那个鬼东西把电池弄坏了
Whatever that thing is, it killed the battery.
快点，野兽
Come on, Beast.
那是什么？
What is that?
绝对不是好事
That's not good.
那到底是什么鬼东西？
What the hell is that?
有可能是什么海军超级机密演习吗？
Do you think that this could be some super-secret Navy surprise exercise?
如果是的话，他们也玩太大了
Because if so, they have gone way too far.
舵手，给他们一点警告
Let's give them a warning, Helmsman.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
这是什么鬼东西？
What the hell is this?
我从军可不是为了这个！ - 对啊
I didn't sign up for this bullshit! Yeah, no shit, dude.
通讯断线，两分钟内应可恢复
Klyvich is offline. Should be back in two minutes.
收到，发信号给JPJ号
Copy that. Signal the John Paul Jones.
开炮示警，一发炮弹，目标左边10里
Fire a warning shot. One round, ten mil, left offset.
设定51倍口径炮架为遥控
Place Mount 51 in remote,
连发模式
batteries released.
炮架设定完成
WEAPONS OFFlCER: Mount 51 has been designated.
我们在对谁开炮？ - 我不知道
Who are we shooting at? I do not know.
快发动，野兽 - 发动不了
CORA: Let's move it, Beast. WALTER: She's dead in the water.
欧弟，你去下风舵 - 是，长官
Ord, get your ass to the lee helm. Aye, sir.
发射！
MULLENARO: Fire!
不明物体飞向JPJ号
Incoming, headed for the John Paul Jones.
不明物体从空中接近
Unknown, inbound at the horizon.
有反舰巡航导弹，启动近程武器系统
Vampire, vampire, vampire. Killing with ClWS.
虾米碗糕
What kind of chuckwagon...
爆炸的那侧舰桥有人吗？
Were there men out on that bridge wing?
有长官
Yes, sir, there were.
成功了，发动中！
I got it! Firing it up!
快加入作战！
HOPPER: Get in there!
长官
Sir!
射爆它！
Light it up!
哈波在干什么？
MAN: What the hell is Hopper doing?
全速前进
All engines, ahead flank.
是，长官，全速前进！
All engines ahead. Aye, sir!
作战情报中心回报
所有定位雷达都无法锁定
Sir, ClC reports both Spy and Fire control radar cannot lock on.
发射！ - 作战情报中心，发射！
Fire! ClC, fire!
右边有飞弹接近！
Incoming on the right!
来了，来了
JOOD: lncoming, incoming!
我们被打中了！
We're hit!
长官，船身已受损
HELMSMAN: Sir, we have a hull breach.
救我！
Help me!
舵手，回去掌舵！ - 是，长官
Helmsman, get back on the helm! Aye, sir.
连射程序启动
Rapid, continued fire!
不！
No!
带我去JPJ号
Get me to the John Paul Jones.
快点！
Now!
舰桥回报水中无生还者
RADlO OPERATOR: Bridge reports no survivors in the water.
桑普森号全员阵亡
Sampson, all hands lost.
目标维持在防守队形
Targets are holding defensive formation.
舰长在哪里？
Where's the captain? Where is he?
怎么回事？ - 舰长和执行官都死了
What happened? OFFlCER: Captain and XO are dead.
什么？
What?
舰长和执行官都死了！
They're dead! CO and XO are dead.
这里谁负责？
Who's in charge?
下一位高阶军官是谁？
Who's next full senior?
就是你
You are.
船归你管了，长官，你是高阶军官
It's your ship, sir. You're senior officer, sir.
长官，请下命今，我不知道该怎么说
Sir, if you would please just give me an order. I don't know what to do, sir.
进攻，全面攻击
We're going in. Full attack.
这是命令
That's an order.
攻击，长官？真的吗？
Attack, sir? Really?
你要命令，这就是命令，上吧
You wanted an order, that's the order. Let's go.
快点
Let's go!
你们听到了 - 是，长官
You heard him. HELMSMAN: Aye, aye, sir!
所有武器准备好
Ready all guns.
发射控制器离线中，我需要三分钟
Fire control is offline. I need three minutes.
跟永田说我要进攻，跟不跟随便他
Tell Nagata I'm going in, with or without him.
他疯了
(SPEAKlNG JAPANESE)
他需要支援！
长官，你真的要发动攻击吗？
Sir, do you really want to attack this thing?
对！我要
Yes! Yes, I do.
长官，妙高号被打中了
JlMMY: Sir, that's a hit! The Myoko was hit, sir.
武器准备好了吗？
Are the weapons ready?
长官，所有攻击他们的船都被消灭了
Sir, they have killed everything that's fired on them.
把炮准备好，把它干掉
Get the guns online, and we ram this thing.
他们害死我哥和桑普森号的弟兄！
They killed my brother and every man on his ship!
我们没有武器可以攻击
We have no weapons to attack with, sir.
那就设定航向310
Then set course to 3-1-0.
那是撞击路线！你确定吗？
That's a collision course! Are you clear on that?
长官，海里有妙高号的人
WALTER: Sir, there are sailors in the water.
武器准备好了没？我们要干掉它！
Get the guns online and we're going to ram this thing!
长官，妙高号要沈了！
Sir, the Myoko is sinking!
长官，拜托！ - 设定航向310
Sir, please! Set the course to 3-1-0.
长官，水里有生还者！
There are sailors in the water, sir!
右满舵
Hard starboard.
是，长官，右满舵
Hard starboard. Aye, sir!
把他们救上来 - 是，长官
Get them out of the water.  Yes, sir.
发生什么事了？
GUNNER: What's happening?
闭嘴，到底发生什么事？
Shut up, man. What the hell is happening?
为什么他们不攻击了他们在干嘛？
What the hell are they doing? Why aren't they attacking?
他们是外星人吗？
GUNNER: Are those things aliens?
你闭嘴好吗？
Would you please shut up?
我们需要援助！需要航母过来！
GUNNER: We need help! We need to get the carrier over here!
谁在管这艘船？ - 哈波
Who's running the ship? Hopper.
开什么玩笑？哈波当老大？
Are you kidding me? Hopper's running the ship?
搞屁啊
This is bullshit.
我们死定了！
We're all going to die!
那到底是什么鬼东西？
What the hell are those things?
那是什么东西？
What is that shit?
美国海军基地夏威夷欧胡岛
卡内奥赫湾
通讯断了，你那边有讯号吗？
BASE OFFlCER: Comms are down up here. You got anything?
所有频道都不通
PlLOT 1: That's a negative on all frequencies.
妈的
Oh, shit.
撤离！
HELlCOPTER GUNNER: Abandon 9-30!
关掉引擎！
PlLOT 2: Kill the engines!
好球！
Strike!
杰克！
MAN: Hey, Jack!
爸？
Dad?
长官，我无法解释
SHANE: Sir, I can't explain this.
我们和另一边完全失去联络
We've lost communication with everyone on the other side of the barrier.
我们进不去，他们也出不来
We can't get in and they can't get out.
范围广达海拔30万尺
CHAlRMAN: The field, whatever it is, extends about 300,000 feet in altitude
深度约2里
and has a depth of about two nautical miles.
我们和太平洋舰队的史恩司令有联系
COMMANDANT: We are in contact with Admiral Shane of Pacific Fleet.
目前，我们的海军被封锁在外围
Right now, our navy is effectively trapped outside the area.
所以里面没有我们的人？
So we have nobody in there?
长官，有三艘导弹驱逐舰的位置无法确认
Sir, we have three guided missile destroyers still unaccounted for.
所以可以说里面还有我们的人
So, it's conceivable we do have somebody inside.
是谁？
Who?
好了，谢谢你！
Okay. Thank you!
舰长！舰长
Captain! Captain!
快点！快点！
YUGl: Let's go! Let's go!
这座山我祖母也爬得动
My grandmother could climb this mountain.
凡事从简单做起
It's a start, Mick.
那是什么？
What was that?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
你们在这里干什么？
What the hell are you guys doing up here?
我要你们立刻下山
I need you off this mountain, right now.
等等，怎么回事？为什么？
Wait, what's going on? Why?
岛上遭受攻击
The island's under attack.
被谁攻击？
Attack by who?
我不知道，有人说是外星人
I don't know. People are using the word "aliens."
外星人？
Aliens?
我们不清楚
We don't know.
那东西摧毁了海军基地
Whatever it is, it took out the marine base
上山的路也全都毁了
and all roads leading to this mountain have been destroyed.
手机、无线电、网路都断讯
Cell phones, radios, lnternet, everything is shut down.
海军才在外海交战
The Navy's engaged, just off of the coast.
海军？
The Navy?
请你和你朋友马上下山
I need you and your friend off of this mountain right now.
我们走吧
Come on, let's go.
维克，把车留下做路障
Vic, leave your car here. We'll go block the road.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
米克！你要去哪里？
Mick! Where are you going?
我没看过外星人，你看过吗
I ain't never seen an alien. Have you ever seen an alien?
米克！别留我一个人在这里
Mick! Don't leave me alone.
你看到了吗7那是什么？
Bra, you saw that? What the hell was that?
文森，你看到了吗？
Hey, Vince, did you see that?
看起来像喷射机
VlNCE: It looked like a jet.
兄弟，我从没
Bra, I've never...
我的天啊！搞什么
Oh, my God! What the hell? (SCREAMS)
长官，我们需要你
Sir, we need you.
现在就需要
We need you now.
我办不到
I can't.
如果你办不到
If you can't...
还有谁办得到？
Who can?
舰长
Captain.
在哪里找到的？
HOPPER: Where did we find it?
他们其中一架运输器在途中坠毁
JlMMY: One of their transporters must have crashed
到处都是残骸
on the way to the island. There was debris everywhere.
汤玛斯和帕兹用爪钩捞上来的
Thomas and Potts fished him right out of the water with a grappling hook.
我就说是个坏主竟，但他们拼命拉
I told them it was a bad idea, but they kept yanking.
我一直叫他们住手，他们还是
I kept telling them "no," and they kept...
妈的！
God damn it!
野兽，给我手电筒
Beast, flashlight.
我爸说他们会来，说了一辈子
My dad said they would come. He said it my whole life.
“宇宙不只有人类”，他说
He said, "We ain't alone."
“总有一天会找到他们”，他说
He said, "One day we would find them,
“或者他们会发现我们”
"or they would find us."
他还说什么你知道吗？
You know what else he said?
他说
He said...
“那天来临时，希望我不在了”
"l hope I ain't around when that day comes."
他还活着！他还活着
He's not dead! He's not dead!
没死！没死！
Not dead! Not dead!
我有不祥的预感
I've got a bad feeling about this.
哪种不祥的预感？
What kind of bad feeling?
我们需要离开地球的那种
Like, "We're going to need a new planet" kind of bad feeling.
医疗警报，C53区，两人受伤
RADlO OFFlCER: Medical casualty, C-53. Two men down.
他们还在船上
They're still on the ship.
全面封锁！
Lock down the ship!
大家没事吧？ - 都没事，士官长
Is everyone all right? OFFlCER 1: All good, Chief.
大家都在吗？
Is everyone accounted for?
第四层有动静
OFFlCER 2: (ON RADlO) Just heard something on Level Four.
蕾克丝，上去
Raikes, up.
快！快！
Hey! Move, move!
你看到什么？
HOPPER: What do you see?
看得到吗？
Did you see it?
没有 - 没有，长官
No, sir. I got nothing, sir!
没有
Nothing.
他情况怎么样？
How is he?
不好，长官
Not good, sir. Not good.
你们两个，带他去医务室，快！
You two, get him to medical, now!
蕾克丝，你跟我来，走吧！
Raikes, you're with me. Let's go!
离开这里！
Get out of here!
不行！
No!
蕾克丝
HOPPER: Raikes...
去作战情报中心
Get your ass to ClC.
现在！
Now!
来吧
Come on.
蕾克丝，你最好已经到了
Raikes, you better be there.
快点，快点
Come on, come on, come on.
你好，白痴！
Mahalo, mother...
我们得下山
We got to get off this mountain.
钥匙在警察的皮带上，你得过去拿
The cop left the keys on his belt. You've got to go down and get them.
你办得到
You can do it.
紧急呼叫，有人听到吗？
This is an emergency call. Can anyone hear me?
无线电测试，有人听到吗？完毕
Radio check. Can anyone hear me? Over.
喂，等我！别走，别走！
Hey, wait up! Don't leave! Don't leave!
不要动！ - 别开枪！
Stop right there! Don't shoot!
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是卡尔，我们发送讯号
I'm Cal Zapata. We sent out a beacon.
妈的，他是生化人吗？
Oh, shit, is he a cyborg?
你们是一伙的？
Are you guys with them?
如果他是人类，叫他把枪放下好吗？
If he's human, could you have him put the gun down?
米克，把枪放下
SAM: Mick, put your gun down.
我跟他们说这种事可能会发生
I told them that something like this could happen.
我说，这就像哥伦布和印第安人
I said, it's going to be like Columbus and the lndians,
或是征服者和印第安人
or the Conquistadors and the lncans.
他们只觉得，不会啦，他们会很友善
They just thought, "No, they will be sweet."
他们杀了我的研究生
They killed my grad student.
冷静下来 - 我没办法冷静
Okay, calm down. I can't.
慢慢呼吸，坐下 - 我无法呼吸
Slow. Sit down. I can't breathe.
呼吸慢一点
SAM: Slow breaths, slow breaths.
你吓到他了，米克
You're freaking him out, Mick.
我觉得他本来就是小孬种
I doubt it takes much to freak him out.
我们需要海军陆战队、陆军，所有人
We need the Marines. We need the Army. We need all of them.
中国官方认为，撞击香港的
NOGRADY: It is the strong belief of the Chinese that what crashed into Hong Kong
是某种通讯船舰
was some sort of communications ship.
你是说一个会飞的电话亭
You're saying that a flying telephone cratered
撞死了两万多人？
and took out 25,000 people?
我是说，来访的这些客人似乎急于
What I'm saying is that our visitors seem extraordinarily concerned
建立与家乡的联系管道
with establishing a line of communication home.
如果失去通讯船，他们要怎么做？
If they have lost their communication ship, how could they do that?
跟我们以往的做法一样
The same way we did.
我们的夏威夷基地有办法
Our communications station in Hawaii has the ability
透过L7卫星将讯息传至外太空
to send a message to deep space via the Landsat 7 satellite.
他们应该是为了那个装置罩住夏威夷
I believe it's for that asset they have domed the islands.
这将会是个种族灭绝的灾难
We're looking at an extinction-level event.
任何军事行动最重要的部分就是
The most critical part of any military operation.
建立通讯战力补给，后勤执行
Establish communications, reinforcements, follow-on forces.
你是说ET想打电话回家？
You're saying E.T. wants to phone home?
那就完蛋了
That would be incredibly, incredibly bad.
到目前为止，也才五艘船
So far, only five ships have made contact.
五艘就弄成这样，来50艘
If five ships can do this, what do you think 50 can do,
500、5千或50万艘怎么办？
or 500 or 5,000 or 500,000?
长官，请给我一点时闻
JlMMY: Sir, if I could just have a minute.
一下下就好
If you'll just give me one second...
给我看蜥蜴干嘛？
Why am I staring at a lizard?
这是我的宠物，长官，潘妮洛普三世
Because this is my pet lizard, sir. Penelope the Third.
所以呢？他们的眼睛是一样的
And? And they have the exact same eyes.
给你15秒，计时开始
You have 15 seconds. Go.
好，长官，我戴了他们的面罩
Okay, sir, I put the helmet on,
基本上是个很厉害的墨镜
and the helmet is, basically, extreme sunglasses.
可以进行水合作用、饱和氧气
And it's some hydration and some oxygen saturation,
还有一堆我不懂的东西
and a bunch of other stuff I don't understand.
有一次我带潘妮洛普去海边，烂主意
But we took Penelope to the beach one time, which was a terrible idea.
她就发神经了，因为她受不了阳光
She went absolutely crazy because she can't handle the sunlight.
你懂吗？我觉得外星人也受不了阳光
You see? I don't think that they can handle the sunlight either.
你试穿过别的装备吗？
You try anything else on?
没有,长官
Negative, sir.
只试了面罩 - 只试了面罩
Just the helmet. Just the helmet.
“头条新闻”
科学家已确认外星人的到访
Scientists have confirmed there was a UFO landing
他们降落在大平洋夏威夷外海
in the Pacific Ocean, off the coast of Hawaii.
今天我想跟国人说明
Today I want to update the American people
目前夏威夷的情况
on what we know about the situation in Hawaii.
首先，我们将动用所有的资源
First, we are bringing all available resources to bear.
这个消息已造成全球恐慌
NEWSCASTER: The news has sparked global unrest as populations panic,
世界各地出现前所未有的动乱
unleashing an unprecedented wave of chaos across the world.
多国政府已宣布戒严令
Many governments have declared martial law.
尽快派出战斗机，司令
MAN: Just scramble the jets, Admiral.
我们得进去！
We need to get in there!
这点我比你更清楚
I'm far from more aware than you of the need to get inside there.
但平白牺牲兵力也无济于事
But wasting lives will not help.
你要我再派战机？
You want me to send up another plane?
你来当副驾驶，我就马上派！
I'll do it the second you come up here and put your ass in the co-pilot's seat, sir!
他们在传送讯息吗？
Are they transmitting?
可能，但没有用
They could be, but it wouldn't do them any good.
没有卫星接收
There's no satellite to receive the transmission.
我们是利用L7卫星
We beam to Landsat 7.
那是什么？
What's Landsat 7?
我们的高轨道卫星
It's our deep-space satellite.
每24小时才会回到转射点
It only orbits into range once every 24 hours.
卫星什么时候就位？
When is the satellite in position?
早上8点43分
8:43 a.m.
还有大约5小时
We've got about five hours.
到时他们就可以利用它传送讯号
And then they will use it to slingshot their transmission.
传去哪里？
Slingshot where?
我不知道，看他们从哪里来
I don't know. Wherever it is they're from.
珍珠港在这，我们大概在这
HOPPER: Pearl Harbor here, we're approximately here,
他们那什么鬼东西应该在中间
and they, whatever they are, are somewhere in the middle.
我们又被困在这里
We're trapped out here.
现在只知道无法锁定他们
What we know right now is we can't target them
除非看得见他们
unless we have a plain line of sight.
没有雷达就无法追踪他们，对吧？
Without radar, we have no way to track them, correct?
没错，但我认为他们也看不到我们
Correct. But I don't think they can see us, either.
为什么？ - 因为我们还活着
Why? Because we are still alive.
好，所以我们看不到彼此
Okay, so they can't see us and we can't see them.
我们无法在安全距离内攻击他们
And we have no way to hit them from a safe distance.
有个办法 - 你有？
There is a way. A way?
可以不用实际看到他们来进行追踪
A way of seeing them, without seeing them.
你该不会要引用孙子兵法吧？
You're going to reference Art of War right now, aren't you?
怎么做？“不知战之地”？
What are we supposed to do, fight the enemy where they aren't?
“水因地而制行？”
Move like water?
我读六遍了，还是看不懂
Because I've read that thing six times. It makes no sense.
那本是中文书
That book is Chinese.
我还是不懂
It still makes no sense.
我的办法简单多了
My way is much more simple.
我们用你们来测试已经20年了
We've been doing it to America for 20 years.
水量位移
Water displacement.
水量位移要怎么侦测？
How do you track water displacement?
海啸预警浮标 - 海啸预警浮标？
Tsunami buoys. Tsunami buoys?
你们在岛的周围都放满了浮标
You have them surrounding your islands,
用来发送移位数据
transmitting displacement data.
我们拦截讯号，算出座标
We hack into their transmissions, form a grid.
没有雷达就无法拦截
You can't track anything without radar.
我不需要雷达
I don't need radar.
只要无线电频率
Just the radio frequencies.
请关掉雷达
Turn off Aegis radar, please.
这家伙哪来的？
JlMMY: Who is this guy?
摩尔士官长 - 长官
Chief Moore. OFFlCER: Sir.
准备相位阵列雷达
Secure SPY.
长官，相位阵列雷达准备中
OFFlCER: Securing SPY, sir.
显示国家海洋局大气总署数据
Display NOAA data.
海洋局大气总署数据？
NOAA data?
没错
That's correct.
你听到了，显示海洋暨大气总署数据
You heard him. Display NOAA data.
“国家海洋局大气总署”
(CLEARS THROAT)
那是什么鬼东西？
CORA: What the hell is that?
是浮标
HOPPER: It's a buoy.
被浪打到时会传送讯号
If it gets hit by a wave, it transmits a signal.
再把航海图重叠上去
Bring up chart plot.
航海图放上去
Chart plot. Bring it up.
“JPJ号”
这样没有雷达也可以追踪
So we can track without radar.
我们当作紧急应变计划来练习
We would practice it as a contingency plan.
你真是个肮脏、奸诈、狡猾
You dirty, cheating, sneaky...
兵不厌诈
Rough world.
我喜欢
I like it.
舰长
Captain.
我的位子就是你的位子
My chair is your chair, sir.
我哥也会做一样的事
My brother would have done the same.
真希望能联络上哈波
I wish we could get a hold of Hopper.
哈波是谁？
Who's Hopper?
他是伯克级驱逐舰的战略行动官
He's a tactical actions officer on an Arleigh Burke class destroyer.
火力足以把整座山铲平
It has the resources that could take this entire mountain out.
大好了，有道理，打给他吧
Great, that makes a lot of sense. Let's call him.
没办法，所有通讯都不通
We can't. Everything is jammed.
他们用电磁波阻档我们的讯号
They're using an electromagnetic field to block our signals.
波段有规律，并非无法突破
It's more like a pulse, it's not a brick wall. There are gaps, okay?
从管制区内也许有办法发话求救
From inside the barrier, we might just be able to get a call out.
如果能拿到光谱分析仪，理论上来说
If I could get to my spectrum analyzer, then, theoretically,
我们就可以找到频率广播
we could find a frequency we could broadcast on...
你有可以发讯号的仪器吗？
Do you have a piece of equipment that can make a call?
有 - 去拿
Yeah. Get it.
没办法，东西在被外星人占领的那里
I can't because it's down there, in that nest of aliens.
你给我去拿
You're going to go get it.
不要
No.
要
Yes. SAM: Yes.
我们找出水量位移的模式
We are looking for patterns of water displacement.
那个浮标在水面下
HOPPER: That buoy is underwater.
那是他们
That's a ship.
准备攻击 - 是，长官
Get on your gun. Yes, sir.
目标E-1-1
Target, Echo-1-1.
收到，E-1-1
CORA: Roger. Echo 1-1.
准备发射
Ready to fire.
发射之后，他们就会知道我们的地点
When we fire, they will know where we are.
发射！
Fire!
欧弟，打中了吗？
Ordy, anything?
没有，长官，没打中
JlMMY: Negative, sir. It's a miss.
他们朝我们过来了
It's heading towards us.
准备好了吗？
You ready?
对不起，但我不可能过去
I'm sorry, but there is no possible way that I'm going down there.
我没有那种胆量
I do not possess that kind of courage.
你现在就给我生出勇气
Right now, you're going to acquire that courage,
不然我就把义肢塞进你屁眼
or I'm going to break my steel leg off into your ass.
了解？
You feel me?
知道了
I feel you.
上，就是现在
Go, now.
要有勇气
Acquiring courage.
怎么了？
What?
F-2-4 F-2-4
Foxtrot, 2-4.  CORA: Foxtrot, 2-4.
准备发射 - 发射！
Ready to fire. Fire!
欧弟，打中了吗？
Ordy, anything?
没有，长官
JlMMY: Negative, sir.
真是超笨的主意
It's a stupid, nincompoop idea.
另一艘来了
There's another one.
飞弹来了！他们从两边包夹！
JlMMY: Incoming, incoming! Sir, they're coming from both directions!
全速后退
Engines, back, full.
来了，来了！
Incoming, incoming, incoming!
1-3-7
India 3-7.
1-3-7，装填完毕
India 3-7. Loaded.
第二个座标，R-2-6
Second coordinate, Romeo, 2-6.
R-2-6
Romeo 2-6.
长官，这里准备好了，随时可发射
Sir, we're hot over here. Missiles good to go.
炸掉他们吧，永田舰长
Let's light them up, Captain Nagata.
永田舰长
Captain Nagata.
发射！
Fire!
畦靠！中了，长官！
Holy shit! A hit, sir! Hit!
这是求救讯号，有人在线上吗？
MlCK: Any station this net, any station this net, this is a call for help.
战舰、警察或军事人员请回答，完毕
Any warship, police or military personnel, please respond, over.
这是JPJ号，表明身分与位置，完毕
This is U.S.S. John Paul Jones,state your identity and position. Over.
哈波？
Hopper?
珊珊？
Sam?
你没事吧？你在哪里？
Sam, are you okay? Where are you?
感谢上帝，我没事
Thank God. I'm okay.
听我说，外星人在马鞍岭信号站
Listen, they're here at the satellite array at Saddle Ridge, do you copy?
他们要传送讯号，建立连线
They're going to transmit a signal and establish communication.
你得摧毁设施，只剩四个小时
You need to destroy the facility. We have four hours.
四个小时，收到
Four hours, I copy.
哈波
Hopper.
听得到吗？
SAM: Can you hear me?
宝贝，你得离开那里
Babe, you need to get out of there.
哈波？哈波？
Hopper? Hopper?
断线了，断线了
No, they're gone. They're gone.
我们最好快走
MlCK: We better get gone, too.
我觉得伯克级驱逐舰
I'm thinking an Arleigh Burke class destroyer
很快就会狂轰这山顶
is about to rain hell down on this mountaintop.
准备好再轰一艘了吗？
Are you ready to kill another one?
T-1-9
Tango 1-9.
T-1-9，装填完毕
Tango 1-9. Loaded.
W-2-5
Whiskey 2-5.
蕾克丝，你追踪得到他们的船吗？
Raikes, can you get a track on their ship?
不行，长官，它到处跑
Negative, sir, it's moving all over the place.
航线预测不出来
I can't get a line on it.
那王八蛋真的乱闪
This sucker's really jumping around.
很聪明
Very intelligent.
日出时间几点？
What time is sunrise?
40分钟后，长官
CORA: Forty minutes, sir.
咱们带他们去他们最不想去的地方
Let's take these bastards somewhere they don't want to go.
全体就备战部署，全体就备战部署
CORA: General quarters, general quarters. All hands, man your battle stations.
我要知道在这边能否稳住
I need to know when we round this point if we can hold her tight.
钻石头山这里
Right around Diamond Head, here.
那里有急流，不触礁很难
WALTER: There's a brutal current there.It will take a miracle to keep her off the reef.
欧弟，可不可能？你办得到吗？
Ordy, is it possible? Can you do it?
不是不可能
It's not impossible.
长官，我可以试试，但我不知道
Sir, I can try, but I don't know what...
行或不行？
Can you do it, yes or no?
目标7里外，快速接近中
Contact is seven miles out, and closing fast.
行，长官，我办得到
Yes, sir, I can do it.
枪炮检查完成
Check safe, check clear. Check safe, check clear.
准备好
Get some.
永田舰长，你射击准不准？
Captain Nagata, how good is your aim?
非常准
Excellent.
好，转向吧！ - 是，长官
OFFlCER: All right, let's start this turn! JOOD: Aye, sir!
左满舵！ - 左满舵，长官！
Left, hard rudder! Left, hard rudder, sir!
情况如何？- 都是暗礁
How are we looking? It's all reef.
欧弟，太近了！往左！
Ordy, you are way too close! Come left!
小心
Easy...
我们会触礁，欧弟！
We're about to kiss these rocks, Ordy!
欧弟！
Ordy!
你在哪里学射击的？
HOPPER: Where did you learn to shoot?
我不知道英文要怎废说
I'm not sure how you say it in English.
“那兹”营
Natsu campu.
“夏吝”营
Summer campu.
现在呢？- 太近了
How about now? GUNNER: Still a little tight.
快搁浅了，欧弟，拜托！
I can see fish, Ordy. Come on, man.
目标距离2里
CORA: Contact, two miles out.
目标预计抵达时间，21秒
Contact ETA, 21 seconds.
“夏吝”营
Summer campu.
目标距离700码
CORA: Contact, 700 yards out.
夏今营？
Summer camp.
我12岁就拿冠军
Champion, when I was 12.
你在开玩笑吗？
Are you kidding me?
来了
Here we go.
听我下令
On my mark.
Three.
Two.
One.
发射
Light them up.  Boom.
再3里马鞍岭即进入射程
OFFlCER: (ON RADlO) Three miles until Saddle Ridge is within range.
武器状况
Status of weps.
长官，他们正从军火室搬上来
JOOD: Sir, they're bringing up all the rounds from the lower mag right now.
长官
JlMMY: Sir.
撤离舰桥，撤离舰桥！
Clear the bridge. Clear the bridge!
妈的！
Shit!
欧弟，起来！快走！
Ordy, get up! Let's go!
快快快！
Go, go, go!
这里两人受伤！
SAlLOR 1: We've got two down, sir!
起来
Get up.
快快快！跳下去！快！
SAlLOR 2: Go, go, go! Get in the water! Go!
船要沉了！
It's going down!
快点
Come on.
蕾克丝！
Raikes!
就在这里！你快到了，加油！
Right here! You're almost there, come on!
来吧，我们得跳船！
Let's go, we have to jump!
那是JPJ号
SAM: That's the John Paul Jones.
那是哈波的船
That's Hopper.
别紧张，珊珊，我看到很多救生艇
Relax, Sam. I'm seeing a lot of lifeboats in the water.
你说卫星三小时后会到位？
You say that satellite will be in position in three hours?
对
Yeah, that's correct.
所以如果错过了，他们就得等
So if they miss it, they have to wait.
我的程式很稳定，不会错过的
My uplink never misses. It's not going to miss.
你开车技术如何？
How are your driving skills?
那是什么意思？我开得超烂
What does that mean? How are my driving skills? They're horrible.
我不是问你
Not your driving.
珊珊，你开车技术如何？
Sam, how are your driving skills?
很好
Good.
看看是否能为世界拖延多一天的时闻
Let's see if we can't buy the world another day.
哪有人这样说话的？
Who talks like that?
上车就对了，走吧
MlCK: Just get in the vehicle. Let's go.
我不要上车，这是你们的事情
I'm not getting in. This is your show, now.
我不想死，多谢了
I don't have a death wish, thank you very much.
再见，各位
Goodbye, everyone.
停车！停车！
Stop! Stop.
这是我的
This is my property.
还没结束
It doesn't end like this.
你要我们怎么做，哈波？
What do you want us to do, Hopper?
我们没有船了
We have no ships left.
还有一艘
We have one.
我们还有一艘战列舰
We have got a battleship.
你疯啦？那是座博物馆
Are you crazy? That's a museum.
今天不是
Not today.
密苏里号――1944年6月下水，衣阿华级战列舰3号舰，舷号BB-63。
全长270.4米，早期装备为50倍口径的16英寸主炮，排水量45,000吨，蒸汽涡轮机机组，212,000马力，最大航速31节。
这艘船70岁了，装备完全过时
This ship is 70 years old. It's totally outdated.
发射系统还是手动的
The firing systems are all analog.
引擎已经10年没发动过
The engines haven't been started in a decade.
那也还好，但我不会发动蒸汽引擎
Which would be fine, but they are steam,which I have no idea how to fire up.
就算花六周时间详读使用手册
And even if I had a user's manual and six weeks to go through it all,
我们也没有足够的兵力
we still don't have enough crew to fire it up.
我不知道你怎么想，长官
I don't know what you're thinking, sir.
大家都没事吧？
Is everyone all right?
是，长官，我们没事
Yes, sir. We're okay.
各位对国家贡献良多
You men have given so much to your country,
没有人有权利再要求你们卖命
and no one has the right to ask any more of you,
但我要请你们帮忙
but I'm asking.
你需要什么，年轻人？
What do you need, son?
我要借你们的船
I need to borrow your boat.
动作快！
年轻人
Son.
长官
Sir.
你要站在那瞪着我看？
What the hell? Are you going to stand there, staring at me?
要看就去当侦察员
Get your goddamn eye on that spotter!
开始侦察，长官
Eye on spotter, sir.
在驱逐舰服过役是吧？
Been working on a destroyer, haven't you?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
准备好跟老油条一起出海吗？
Are you ready to play with the big boys?
是的，长官
Oh, yes, sir.
来吧，我们需要帮忙
Come on. We need the help.
赞！
Awesome!
你最好捂住耳朵
Best cover your ears.
跟猫咪呼噜声一样悦耳
Purrs like a kitten.
舰桥，主控室报告，八具锅炉烧滚滚
Bridge, main control. I got eight boilers hot.
准备上阵，长官
Ready to rock and roll, sir.
油料状况如何？
How are we looking on fuel?
600吨，长官，只够跑一趟保养厂
600 long tons, sir. Just enough for a maintenance run.
武器状况
Ordnance?
我们尽力了，长官，但量不多
We scraped together what we could, sir. But it's not much.
好，出海吧，我们有事要办
All right, let's get her to sea. We have got work to do.
收到
Roger that.
全速前进
Engines ahead, flank.
是，长官，全速前进
All engines ahead, flank. All engines ahead, flank. Aye, sir.
还好吗？
You good?
很好，长官 - 很好，长官
VETERAN: Good, sir. Good, sir.
好
Good.
1号炮塔状况？
Status of turret one?
中线炮弹就绪
Center line, barrel, armed.
停！ - 安全！
GUNNER: Stop! WALTER: Clear!
炮弹己装填
GUNNER: Loaded.
2号炮塔状况？
VETERAN: Status of turret two?
右舷炮弹就绪
Starboard side, armed.
3号炮塔状况？
VETERAN: Status of turret three?
左舷可以开派对了
Port barrel. Ready to rock and roll.
左舷炮弹就绪！
Port side, armed!
长官，我们真的要炸欧胡岛？
Sir, are we really firing on Oahu?
看起来是这么回事
Sure looks that way.
我的妈！
Holy shit!
五分钟内马鞍岭将进入射程
CORA: Saddle Ridge will be in weapons range in five minutes.
哈，有人要被打屁屁了
Oh, brother, somebody is going to kiss the donkey.
哈波！
Hopper!
我以为那个东西不会动
I didn't think that one moved.
我也是
Me neither.
我的天啊
My God.
开什么玩笑？
Are you kidding me?
孙子兵法
Art of War.
武器室，回报状况
HOPPER: Fire control, weapons status?
目标已瞄准
Aimed at target.
所有炮塔对准方位210
Train all three turrets to 2-1-0.
长官，方向是错的！
CORA: But, sir, that's the wrong direction!
我很清楚，蕾克丝
I'm well aware of that, Raikes.
他在搞什么鬼？
What the hell is he doing?
他又发疯了，老是这样
He's losing his mind, all over again.
左满舵
Hard left rudder.
是，长官，左满舵
Hard left rudder. Aye, sir.
下左锚 - 什么？
Drop port anchor. What?
现在就下锚！
Drop it now!
我们死定了
We are going to die.
你会死我会死
You are going to die. I am going to die.
我们都会死
We are all going to die.
不过不是今天
Just not today.
给这些王八蛋吃大餐
Let's drop some lead on those mother...
发射！
Fire!
重新装填！重新装填！
Reload! Reload!
重设击发装置！舱口关上
Firing mechanism reset! Secure the hatch.
左舷预备！
Port side ready!
把锚放掉
Release the anchor.
飞弹靠近中！
Incoming! Incoming!
你没事吧？
You all right?
绝不能让他们打沉这艘船
They ain't going to sink this battleship, no way.
发射！
Hit it!
全部发射！
Everything you've got!  Whoo!
所有战机都给我升空，快点！
I want every available plane on this ship in the air, now!
我真不敢相信有用！
I can't believe that worked!
是啊，孙子兵法，不知战之地
Yeah, Art of War. Fight the enemy where they aren't.
这么多年来，我终于懂了
After all these years, that finally just clicked.
但那不是这个意思
But that's not what it means.
真的吗？
Really?
差得远了
Not even close.
继续开！
MlCK: Keep going!
妈的！
Oh, shit!
米克，我的腿卡住了
Mick, my leg is stuck.
米克！
Mick!
武器状况？
HOPPER: Status of weapons?
3号炮塔毁了
VETERAN: Turret three is down.
但炮塔后还有一枚炮弹
We got one round of high-explosive back-aft in turret three.
我们过去，叫他们准备好炮弹
Tell them to have it ready when we get there.
让我来
I got this.
野兽，最新消息
Beast, update.
我们要把这颗炮弹送去2号炮台
I need that round. We need to bring it to turret two.
长官？ - 2号炮台有500尺远
Sir? Turret two is 500 feet away.
这炮弹重达1千磅！怎么搬过去？
This round is over a thousand pounds! How do you expect us to get it there?
蕾克丝！去射击站准备好
Raikes! Get to the gun plot, finger on the trigger.
是，长官 - 来吧，小心
Yes, sir. Come on, easy. Easy.
小心，慢点，慢点
GUNNER: Gentle, boys. Gentle, gentle.
快离开！
Get out of here!
我们得走了
We got to go.
冷静点，好吗？我来救你
Calm down, okay? I'm going to frigging save you.
1号炮塔准备就绪
Closed, number one is armed.
坐标？ - T330
Coordinates? Train, 3-3-0.
高度？ - 220
Elevation? 2-2-0.
好了！快！
There! Go!
走吧！
Let's go!
准备好了
She's armed.
希望你不在那里
You better not be up there.
走吧！快点！
Let's go! Come on!
哈波！
Hopper!
我们只剩一颗炮弹，对吧？
We only have one round left, right?
对
Yeah.
和您服役是我的荣幸，舰长
It was an honor serving with you, Captain.
荣幸的是我
The honor was mine.
发射 - 发射
Fire. Fire.
目标锁定
Locked on target.
我们很荣幸地在这里表杨
SHANE: We take great pride in honoring
面对敌军强烈火力却毫无恐惧
the many men and women who demonstrated exceptional gallantry
展现无比勇气的弟兄们
in the face of overwhelming enemy force.
许多官兵的英勇与胆识
Valor and courage were exhibited by so many
我无法一一致意
that I cannot honor them all.
我很荣幸能在此
It is my great privilege to recognize
特别感谢几位杰出官兵
those few whose actions deserve special note.
美国陆军退役中校米克卡纳里
Lieutenant Colonel, United States Army, retired, Mick Canales.
美国总统很荣幸能颁发
The President of the United States takes great pleasure
海军十字勋章给史东哈波中校
in presenting the Navy Cross to Commander Stone Hopper
表扬他的英勇事迹
for extraordinary heroism.
代替他兄长受奖的是
Receiving this award, on behalf of his brother,
艾历斯哈波少校
Lieutenant Commander Alex Hopper.
请留步，哈波先生
Stand fast, Mr. Hopper.
我很荣幸颁发银星勃章给你
It is my great pleasure to present you with a Silver Star
表扬你的出众勇气与战斗精神
for your exceptional heroism and gallantry in combat operations.
我期待你很快就能升任舰长
And I look forward to seeing you at sea on a ship of your own command, soon.
谢谢您
Thank you.
欧弟，先闭嘴一下  快点拍照，野兽
Ordy, stop talking for a second.  Come on, take the picture, Beast.
说“海军” - 海军！
Say "Navy." Navy!
不赖嘛，哈波
Mildly impressive, Hopper.
准备好了离开驱逐舰
You ready to get your ass off that big gray monster,
来科罗纳多基地更上层楼吗？
get out to Coronado and get your hands dirty with the big boys?
是的，长官 - 你觉得你办得到？
Yes, sir. You think you've got what it takes?
我希望是，长官 - 打给我，哈波
I hope so, sir. Call me, Hopper.
只怕会有点无聊
It just might be too much sleep, though, sir.
你怕会觉得无趣？ - 是，长官
A little too much sleep for you? Yes, sir.
等着瞧咯
We will have to see about that.
快点，哈波，跟永田靠近点
Come on, Hopper, cozy up to Nagata.
好可爱
You look so cute.
你们俩像对佳偶 - 我们在拍拖吗？
You guys make a great couple. Are we dating now?
看起来真帅
You look dapper.
说“海军”
"Navy." Say, "Navy."
等一下再拍
Yeah, I don't know. Oh! Bad timing.
恭喜 - 谢谢你
Congratulations. Thank you.
你好吗？ - 我很好，你呢？
How are you? Good, how are you?
我爱你 - 我爱你
I love you. I love you.
我蛮幸运的，你知道吗？
I'm a pretty lucky guy, you know that?
所以现在是跟我爸谈的最好时机
Which is why I think it's a perfect time for you to talk to my dad.
他在哪？我希望他现在就在这
Where is he? I wish he was standing right here.
太好了，你看！
That's perfect, because look!
就在那里，亲爱的去找他吧
Your wish came true, honey. Go get him.
比什么赞，哪有用
Thumbs up, that helps.
长官
Sir.
什么事？
What is it?
我想让您知道，我爱珊珊
I want you to know that I am in love with Sam.
请您允许我娶她
And I am asking your permission to marry your daughter.
不准
No.
谢谢长官，这
Thank you, sir. I mean, it's...
什么？ - 不准
What? No.
长官
Sir...
我拯救了世界耶
I saved the world.
拯救世界和我女儿是两回事
Saving the world is one thing, Hopper. My daughter is quite another.
但是  - 不准就是不准
But... No means no, Hopper.
失陪了，我午餐时间已经过了
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm late for lunch.
我想来份鸡肉卷饼好了
I think I will have a chicken burrito.
鸡肉？
Chicken...
长官
Sir.
跟我来吧，哈波
Come along, Hopper.
我们边吃边谈你投降的条件
We will discuss the terms of your surrender over a meal.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
她跟你说过鸡肉卷饼的事？
She told you about that?
苏格兰北部高地
比起杰斯你算什么东西
You got nothing on Jay-Z.
连我都把不到碧昂丝好不好
I mean, even I couldn't get Beyonce.
我也把不到
I couldn't get Beyonce either.
当然把不到
No way.
搞什么
Whoa. What the...
那是什么鬼东西？
THOM: What is that?
不要太靠近
Don't get too close to it.
大家快来看！
Whoa, guys! Look at this!
不要太靠近！ - 别跑过去
ANGUS: Don't go too close! THOM: Don't run to it.
你觉得那像不像门？ - 门？
Do you think that looks like a door? ANGUS: A door?
哈罗？ - 有人在家吗？
Hello? Anyone home?
那样哪有屁用
ANGUS: That's not going to help, is it?
这有用吗？
This really helps.
你知道那是什么吗？
THOM: Do you know what that is?
我们觉得里面有东西
RONNlE: We think there's something inside of it.
你要打开吗，吉米
THOM: Are going to open it, Jimmy?
吉米说要进去，他就进得去
If Jimmy says he's getting in, he's getting in!
加油，吉米！
Come on, Jimmy! Whoo!
吉米！
Jimmy!
这就对了，叫我老大
That's it. Come to daddy.
吉米！我的天啊！
ANGUS: Jimmy! Oh, my God!
好耶！
Yes!
THE END
(PANTlNG) (ALL SCREAMlNG)